<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbookxi.rng" type="xml"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>NEXUSe2e Configuration</title>
    <subtitle>Putting NEXUSe2e to Work</subtitle>
    <sect1>
        <title>Defining the Identity of your Server</title>
        <para> </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Adding a Communication Partner</title>
        <para> </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Adding a Business Process (Choreography)</title>
        <para> </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Securing the Communication</title>
        <para> </para>
        <sect2>
            <title>Requesting your own Certificate</title>
            <para>In order to obtain a certificate you need to create a certificate request. This
                will contain information about your organization and more sprecifically about the
                server that is to be authenticated through the certificate. You then need to submit
                the request to a certificate authority (CA) of your choice. The CA will return your
                certificate that contains the information that you have provided plus their digital
                signature that establishes the trust in your certificate.</para>
            <para>You can use NEXUSe2e to create a certificate request or use third party tools that
                you might already use or are most familiar with.</para>
            <figure>
                <title>Requesting your own Certificate</title>
                <screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata width="14cm" fileref="images/chapter_3/cert_request_overview.png" />
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </screenshot>
            </figure>
            <caution>
                <para>When the certificate request gets created the system also generates the so
                    called public and private key pair that is the basis for the cryptographic
                    mechanism on which digital certificates are built. These keys are automatically
                    associated with the request in the NEXUSe2e system. When you delete the
                    certificate request these keys will be lost. Any certificate that gets issued by
                    a CA for such a deleted request will be rendered useless. Creating a new request
                    with the same information will not create the same key pair again and will not
                    match the certificate.</para>
            </caution>
            <para>To create a new certificate request navigate to NEXUSe2e > Server Configuration >
                Certificates > Certificate Request > Create Request. The following screen will
                appear:</para>
            <figure>
                <title>Entering the Certificate Request Information</title>
                <screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata width="14cm" fileref="images/chapter_3/cert_request_create.png" />
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </screenshot>
            </figure>
            <para>Enter the information for your company and server. The Common Name is the name the
                server is know under to parnter companies i.e., on the Internet e.g.,
                b2b.mycompany.com.</para>
            <caution>
                <para>Make sure you remember the password you enter on this screen. It will be used
                    later to protect your certificate. The password will also be applied to any
                    backups of your certificate that you can create through the NEXUSe2e UI.</para>
                <para>Once you have entered and saved your certificate request it is a good idea to
                    create a backup of your data by navigating to the screen 'Export Full Key
                    Information (Backup)' which will let you save a backup of your request and key
                    pair to a file.</para>
            </caution>
            <para>For submitting the request data to a CA you will need to provide them with your
                request data in a specific format which is typically pasted to a text area on the CA
                web page. The required data can be found on the screen 'Show Request' in the field
                'PEM Encoded Request'.</para>
            <figure>
                <title>The Certificate Request Data ready for Submission to a CA</title>
                <screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata width="14cm" fileref="images/chapter_3/cert_request_view.png" />
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </screenshot>
            </figure>
            <para>To import the certificate received from the CA navigate to the screen 'Import
                Certificate'. The screen will allow you to browse to the file on your file system
                and on confirming the import a screen will appear to verify the information of the
                loaded certificate.</para>
            <figure>
                <title>Importing the Certificate received from the CA</title>
                <screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata width="14cm" fileref="images/chapter_3/cert_request_import.png" />
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </screenshot>
            </figure>
            <para>When you accept the import the certificate will be combined with the
                private/public key pair from the original request and a keystore containing this
                information will be saved in the 'Certificate Staging' area.</para>
            <figure>
                <title>Imported Certificate in Certificate Staging area</title>
                <screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata width="14cm" fileref="images/chapter_3/cert_staging_list.png" />
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </screenshot>
            </figure>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Importing a Keystore/Certificate created with other Tools</title>
            <para>To load a new certificate into NEXUSe2e it is recommended that you load it into
                the certificate staging area first. Navigate to NEXUSe2e -&gt; Communications
                -&gt; Certificates -&gt; Certificate Staging and select 'Import
                Certificate'. Select the certificate file to import, provide the password and click
                'Update' to import. Note that the file has to contain the certificate and your so
                called private key. The file has to be in PKCS12 format which is typically indicated
                by a .p12 or .pfx file extension.</para>

            <figure>
                <title>Importing the new certificate into the staging area</title>

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/chapter_3/staging_import.png" />
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>

            <para>Once the required certificate has been imported into the staging area you can
                promote it to production. Please note that this will replace the previously
                configured active certificate and that the operation cannot be undone. In order to
                promote a certificate navigate to NEXUSe2e -&gt; Communications -&gt;
                Certificates -&gt; Certificate Staging and click on the certificate entry. This
                will display further details of the certificate and additional operations for it.
                Select the 'Promote this Certificate' button. To verify that the promotion worked
                see section 'Check the status of your Certificate'.</para>

            <figure>
                <title>Promoting the new certificate into production</title>

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/chapter_3/promote_certificate.png" />
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Configuring CA Certificates</title>
            <para> </para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Securing the Web Application Server</title>
            <subtitle>Synchronize Tomcat Certificate with NexusE2E</subtitle>

            <para>In addition to configuring the NexusE2E application with the new certificate the
                underlying Tomcat Web application server needs to be configured with it as well.
                Tomcat requires the certificate to be available as a file in the file system.
                Identify the file location of the certificate currently configured in Tomcat by
                reviewing the file &lt;install dir&gt;/conf/server.xml. Find the section
                that starts with 'Connector port="xxxx"' where xxxx is the SSL enabled port of your
                Tomcat server. Verify that this file location points to the same file that is
                defined in the file &lt;install dir&gt;/NexusE2E/WEB-INF/web.xml. The file
                definition can be found in the section 'PrivateKeyStore'. Additionally the
                certificate password configured in the server.xml files needs to match the one used
                when importing the certificate into NexusE2E. In case they differ the server.xml
                file needs to be updated to reflect the password used in the NexusE2E application.</para>

            <para>In order to export the certificate from NexusE2E to Tomcat navigate to NEXUSe2e
                -&gt; Communications -&gt; Certificates -&gt; Server Certificate in the
                web based administration UI and select the button 'Export this Certificate Chain'.
                Verify that path listed under 'Predefined Path' matches the file location in the
                server.xml file. If it does not select the radio button in front of 'Different
                Position' and provide the correct file location in the text field. Click the
                'Export' button to save the file to the file system.</para>

            <figure>
                <title>Export the server certificate to Tomcat</title>

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/chapter_3/export_server_certificate.png" />
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>

            <para>After the file has been successfully exported the Tomcat server needs to be
                restarted.</para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>

</chapter>
