<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbookxi.rng" type="xml"?>
<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" version="5.0">
    <info>
        <title>NEXUSe2e Server Manual</title>
        <subtitle>Version 4</subtitle>
        <author>
            <orgname>X·ioma GmbH</orgname>
            <address>
                <city>Hamburg</city>
                <street>Schulterblatt 36</street>
                <postcode>20357</postcode>
                <country>Germany</country>
            </address>
            <email>support@xioma.de</email>
        </author>
    </info>
    <preface>
        <title>Welcome to NEXUSe2e</title>
        <para> In the most simplified terms, NEXUSe2e allows software applications to communicate
            with each other and share information.</para>
        <para>These applications may be in the same network (intranet), or may be separated by
            departmental, company, or even national boundaries. When computers talk to each other
            directly the communication is quicker, the transaction is cheaper, and the data is more
            accurate.</para>
        <para>The most common use of this application has been to connect two or more trading
            partners to integrate the supply chain. However, understanding the functionality and
            flexibility of this product will help you to understand how to fully connect with
            applications inside and outside of your firewall. This manual is intended to provide a
            functional and technical understanding of the workings of the NEXUSe2e application.</para>
        <para>There are 2 Major sections to this manual. The first section 'Before Using NEXUSe2e'
            is intended to provide you with an understanding of Business Messaging, and how the
            NEXUSe2e Server works.</para>
        <para>The second section, 'Using the Web Interface' provides an in depth description of the
            system, and the functionality of all of the areas of NEXUSe2e.</para>
        <para>Additionally, there is a 'Frequently Asked Questions' area that links directly to
            common questions and issues.</para>
    </preface>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="chapter_1.xml"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="chapter_2.xml"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="chapter_3.xml"/>
</book>
